PELUMI ADETOYE

Front End Developer

Abeokuta, Ogun • pelumiiadetoye@gmail.com • https://github.com/misspelz

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic and detail-oriented Front End Developer with a good knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and third-party frameworks/libraries such as Tailwind CSS, React and React Native. I seek to utilize my skills to provide value to projects both today and in the future, and aim to take on new challenges and technologies for developing new features and enhancing the overall user experiences.

TECHNOLOGIES

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer (Volunteer), Edustipend

June 2023 - present

Learning Support Agency

- Applies knowledge of React in building UI components and features that satisfy design and product requirements
- Works in close collaboration with technical leadership, the product designer, the product manager and the backend team to fulfill product requirements
- Contributes to the development of the component library system using Storybook
- Designs, develops and writes unit tests for code written in line with the team's defined software development process
- Participates in daily standup and other required team meetings

Front End Developer (Intern), Herlign

May 2023 - present

Venture Studio and Wellness Garden

- Translate UI designs into code using React, creating interactive and responsive user interfaces
- Implement responsive design techniques to ensure a seamless user experience across desktop, tablet, and mobile platforms
- Test and troubleshoot websites to ensure they are compatible with various web browsers, ensuring consistent functionality and appearance
- Participate in team meetings, share progress updates, and actively contribute to discussions

Front End Developer, ITSkillsCenter

Nov. 2022 - May 2023

Software Development & Training Agency

- Developed user-friendly web pages with engaging features
- Created reusable codes that is scalable and optimized in performance
- Worked with the version control system, git, to keep track of codes
- Utilized industry best practices for mobile-first and responsive web design
- Participated in team meetings, contributed ideas and solutions

Front End Developer, Dufuna

Online Graduate Trainee Program

- Created responsive and functional user interfaces
- Maintained brand consistency throughout the design process
- Worked closely with other team members

Web Developer, FemCode Africa

2020

Online Trainee Program

- Learned the basics of HTML5 and CSS3
- Learned to work in a Team

EDUCATION

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun State 2013 - 2017

Bachelor of Science in Physics

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

- Front-End Development Coding BootCamp ITSkillsCenter
- Soft-Skills Training Jobberman

SKILLS/COMPETENCIES

- Clear communication
- Problem solving
- Responsive design
- Debugging
- Team playing

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

- Testing new technologies
- Collaboration
- Researching
- Scrabble
- Monopoly

2021 - 2022